<Document>
# Union of Soviet Socialist Planets Lore Summary

Founded in the year 2250, during the [color=#8B0000]Great Corporate War[/color], the [bold]USSP[/bold] declared independence from a Russian-based mining and extraction company owned by Nanotrasen.
Of course, due to the fact that Nanotrasen was never known for fully giving their workers the benefits they are entitled to by UNE workplace laws,
a great disdain for anything resembling corporate/UNE culture is a common personality trait to any denizen of the [bold]USSP[/bold].

Nova Cygni is one of the few habitable planets under their control, all the others in their main system are volcanic in nature,
making the system great for extraction operations.
That is if they had the proper equipment.
They had it of course, provided by NT, but after years of either neglect or inability to perform proper maintenance they had to resort to extracting raw materials
from either asteroids, moons, or their few habitable planets, severely polluting them.

Hailing from the planet of Nova Cygni in the system of Seerum in the Amygdala Sector, the [bold]USSP[/bold], or the [bold]Union of Soviet Socialist Planets[/bold], emerged onto the galactic sphere as a fierce industrial faction with a population that
passionately supports worker's rights and economic equality.

The leader of the [bold]USSP[/bold] is the [bold]Chairman[/bold], or more commonly known as the [bold]Autarch[/bold]. He serves as the representative of the State and the ruling and only political party, the NSPP (National Socialist Prosperity Party).

The [bold]USSP[/bold] is not a major power in the Colossus Sector as a whole anymore, while they may sometimes be spotted as rogue agents, insurgents, or seemingly peaceful spacers still loyal to their place of birth, they are largely disoriented and cut
off from contact from the faction as a whole.

Alongside the [bold][color=cyan]TSF[/bold][/color] and the [bold][color=#8B0000]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color], they are recognized among the major factions vying for control of the esoteric
[bold][color=047ABD]Monolith[/bold][/color] and its bountiful resources.

</Document>
